They've killed the boy!
They've killed young Paolo!
They've killed your son Paolo!
Murderers! Murderers!
My son...
All my respect, Don Ciccio.
Don Ciccio...
You killed my husband because he wouldn't give in to you.
And his oldest son Paolo...
because he swore revenge.
But Vito is only nine.And dumb-witted.
He never speaks.
It's not his words I'm afraid of.
He's weak. He couldn't hurt anyone.
But when he grows, he'll grow strong.
Don't worry. This little boy can't do a thing to you.
When he's a man, he'll come for revenge.
I beg you, Don Ciccio,spare my only son.
He's all I have left.
I swear to God he'll never do you any harm.
Spare him!
No.
Run, Vito!
Move and I'll kill him!
Kill him...
Any family who hides the boy Vito Andolini will regret it!
You understand?
Anybody who hides the boy
If anyone is hiding the boy Vito Andolini...
...turn him over to us.
Don Ciccio will thank you for it!
Any family who hides the boy Vito Andolini...
Vito, we're praying for you!
Anybody who hides the boy Vito Andolini is in for trouble!
Turn him over to us.
Don Ciccio will thank you for it!
It'll be better for the boy,and better for you!
Any family who hides the boy Vito Andolini...
Nurse.
Interpreter!
Where are you from?
What is your name?
Come on, son. What is your name?
Vito Andolini from Corleone.
Corleone. Vito Corleone.
Okay, over there.
Next.
Your name?
Tell him he has smallpox. Quarantine three months.
Vito Corleone!Vito Corleone!
Here he is. This is him.
Did you bring the car keys?
Laurie! Laurie!
Mama!
Look,who's here?
- Father Carmelo.-
- This is Father Carmelo. - I'm Merle Johnson.
family parish.
Mama!Here I am.
Constanzia,
after one week?
I sent the car to the airport last week to pick you up.
It was chaos.
Anyway, here I am, just one week late.
This is for my mama!
- What is this? - You remember Merle?
Hello,mama.
Hello. How are you? Thank you.
Where's Michael? I gotta to talk to him,
and um, get a few things straight,
and I can't wait on line.
You go see your children first.
Then you worry about waiting on line to see your brother. Like everybody else.
Ladies and gentlemen...
A most distinguished guest would like to say a few words.
Please welcome Senator Pat Geary
of the State of Nevada.
And there is Mrs. Geary.
Thank you very much, Ladies and Gentlemen
This is a very, very happy day for me and my wife Mrs. Geary.
We see Nevada far too seldom.
But today we can join with old friends,
we can make new friends,
and we help celebrate a young man's first Communion.
And also to thank that boy's family for a magnificent contribution to the State.
I have here in my hand a cheque
made out to the university,
and it is a magnificent endowment
in the name of Anthony Vito Corleone.
The cheque is signed by that young man's parents,
whom I think we should recognise.
Mike, Pat, Kay. stand up, please. Let the folks see you!
Folks, I want you to join me
in giving a real Nevada thank you to Mr. and Mrs. Michael Corleone!
We also have, as a special added attraction,
the Sierra Boys Choir,
who have chosen a certain special song
and a special arrangement to
honour their host, Mr. Michael Corleone.
Boys.
The plaque.
Relax.
Okay, fellows, did you get that one?
Now, Senator, just you and Mrs. Corleone.
Okay that's enough, Senator
Give me the cheque.
higher,so we can see it.
My lawyer Tom Hagen.
Senator Geary.
He arranged everything through your man Turnbull.
Yes, yes.
Sit down.
Well I was under the impression that you and I would talk alone.
I trust these men with my life, Senator.
To ask them to leave would be an insult.
Well,
it's perfectly all right with me,
but I am a blunt man
and I intend to speak very frankly to you.
Maybe more frankly than anyone in my position has ever talked to you before.
The Corleone family has done well in Nevada.
You own, or control, two major hotels in Vegas,
and one in Reno.
The licences were grandfathered in,
so there was no problem with the Gaming Commission.
Now my sources tell me
that you plan to make a move against the Tropigala.
They tell me that, within a week,
you're going to move Klingman out.
Quite an expansion.
However, it will leave you with a little technical problem.
The licence will still be in Klingman's name.
Turnbull is a good man.
Yeah, well, let's cut out the bullshit.
I don't want to spend more time here than I have to.
You can have the licence.
The price is 250,000 dollars.
Plus five per cent of the gross monthly,
of all four hotels, Mr. Corleone.
The price for the licence is less than 20,000 dollars,
-Am I right? -That's right.
Why would I pay more than that?
Because I intend to squeeze you.
I don't like your kind of people.
I don't like to see you come out to
this clean country in oily hair,dressed up in those silk suits
and try to pass yourselves off as decent Americans.
I'll do business with you,
but the fact is that I despise your masquerade,
the dishonest way you pose yourself.
Yourself, and your whole fucking family.
Senator...
...we're both part of the same hypocrisy.
But never think it applies to my family.
All right, all right.Some people have to play little games.
You play yours.
Let's say that
you'll pay me because it's in your interest.
I want your answer and the money by noon tomorrow.
One more thing.Don't you contact me again,ever.
From now on you deal with Turnbull.
-Open that door, son. -Senator,
you can have my answer now if you like.
My offer is this:
Nothing.
Not even the fee for the gaming licence
which I would like you to put up personally.
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
Ladies! I didn't know you were out here.
Honey, we have to go. We're 30 minutes late.
Really? I'm sorry.
It's been delightful.
It was our pleasure.
It was wonderful talking to you.
Fredo!
Fredo, you son-of-a-bitch,
you look great!
Frank Pentangeli!
I thought you was never coming out west you big bum!
I've got to check on my boys.
What's with the food here?
-What's the matter? -A kid comes up to mein a white jacket,
gives me a Ritz cracker, and uh, chopped liver, he says Canap茅s.
uh, uh, can o' peas my ass, that's a Ritz cracker and chopped liver!
Hey, does anyone...
We got a barbecue here, so where's the sausage?
Bring out the peppers and sardines!
Seeing you reminds me of New York in the old days!
Hey, Fredo.You remember Willi Cicci
who was with old man Clemenza in Brooklyn?
We were all upset about that.
Heart attack, huh?
No, that was no heart attack.
That's what I'm here
to see your brother Mike about.
- But what's with him? - What do you mean?
Do I have to get a letter of introduction
to get a sit-down?
You can't get in to see Mike?
He's got me waiting in a lobby!
Johnny Ola.
Al Neri.
How are you, Johnny?
Do you know my lawyer Tom Hagen?Johnny Ola.
Sure,I remember Tom from the old days.
Rocco,what's this?
It's an orange from Miami.
Take care of Johnny's men. They look like they might be hungry.
Johnny!
Sit down!
Tom won't stay,Johnny.
He only handles specific areas of the business.
Tom
Sure, Mike.
What are you drinking, Johnny?
Anisette.
If you need anything,Mike,I'll be outside.
Just tell Rocco we're waiting, Tom.
I just left Mr. Roth in Miami.
How is his health?
It's not good.
Is there anything I can do? Anything I can send?
We appreciate your concen Michael and your respect.
That casino...Registered owners: Jacob Lawrence,
Allan Barclay. Beverly Hills attorneys.
The real owners are the old Lakeville Road group
and our friend in Miami.Meyer Klingman runs the store.
he runs a piece of it too,he does alright.
but I've been instructed to tell you
that if you move him out,
our friend in Miami will go along.
It's very kind of him.
Tell him it's greatly appreciated.
Hyman Roth always makes money for his partners.
One by one,
our old friends are gone.
Death
natural or not,
prison, deported...
Hyman Roth is the only one left,
because he always made money for his partners.
I can't believe it!
out of thirty professional musicians,
there isn't one Italian in, in the group here.
Let's have a tarantella! Come on!
You! Up! Clarinet up , up, up!
Questa mano!
What the hell have we here?
I'll see my sister alone.
It concerns me too.Is it okay, Mike, if I stay?
How are you, honey?
You've met Merle, he was with me in Vegas.
I saw him with you.
Could I have a drink or something?
Que voi?
Al, would you please get him a drink!
We're going to Europe next week.
I'd like to book passage on the Queen.
So what do you come to me for?
Why don't you go to a travel agent?
We're getting married first.
The ink on your divorce isn't dry yet,
and you're getting married?
You see your children on weekends.
You know your oldest boy, Victor, was picked up in Reno for some petty theft
-that you don't even know about. -Mikey.
You fly around the world with men who don't even care about you,
-and use you like a whore!-You're not my father!
Then what do you come to me for?
'Cause I need money.
Connie, Connie, Connie...
I wanna be reasonable with you.
Why don't you stay with the family?
You can live on the estate with your kids.
You won't be deprived of anything.
and you can have everything you want.
I don't know this Merle.
I don't know what he does or what he lives on.
Now why don't you tell him marriage is out of the question
and you don't want to see him anymore.
He'll understand, believe me.
Connie.
If you don't listen to me,
and marry this man...
...you'll disappoint me.
What's "Chen dannay"?
"Cent' anni". It means 100 years.
It means we should all live happily for 100 years.
The family.
That'd be true if my father were still alive.
Connie!
Merle!
you've met my sister-in-law Deanna.
Fredo's wife.
- My pleasure.-How do you do.
-They're perfect. -mama.
What did she mean by that?
With all respect,
I didn't come here to eat dinner!
I know, I know.
What's the matter? I just, I just want to dance!
Dancing is one thing, you're fallin' all over the floor.
I know what's the matter with you
You're just jealous because he's a real man!
I swear to God, Deanna, I'm gonna belt you right in the teeth.
You couldn't belt your mama!
You know somethin'? These Dagos
are crazy when it comes to their wives.
Michael says that if you can't take care of this,
I have to.
Maybe you better.
Never marry a Wop.
They treat their wives like shit!
I didn't mean to say Wop.
Ahh, Ahh woo! Rocco! Oh!
What are you doing to me, you big slob? Help!Fredo!
I can't control her, Mikey.
You're my brother,
you don't have to apologize to me.
Clemenza promised the Rosato brothers
three territories in the Bronx after he died.
You took over and didn't give it to them.
- I weltched? -You weltched.
Clemenza promised them lu cazzo,
Clemenza promised them nothing.
He hated those son of a bitches more than I do.
Frankie, they feel cheated.
You're sitting up in the Sierra Mountains
and you're drinking...What's he drinking?
Champagne.
...Champagne cocktails
and passing judgement on
how I run my family.
Your family's still called Corleone.
And you'll run it like a Corleone.
My family doesn't eat here, doesn't eat in Las Vegas...
...and doesn't eat in Miami...
...with Hyman Roth!
You're a good old man, and I like you.
You were loyal to my father for years.
The Rosato brothers are taking hostages.
They spit right in my face,
all because they're backed up by that Jew in Miami.
I know.
That's why I don't want them touched.
- Not touched? - No
I want you to be fair with them.
You want me to be fair with them?
How can you be fair to animals?
Tom, listen. They recruit spics,
they recruit niggers.
They do violence in their grandmothers'neighbourhoods!
And everything with them is whores! And junk, dope!
And they leave the gambling to last.
I want to run my family
without you on my back.
-and I want those Rosato brothers dead! - No.
Mort'
Now I have business that's important with Hyman Roth.
I don't want it disturbed.
Then you give your loyalty to a Jew before your own blood.
Come on, Frankie,
You know my father did business with Hyman Roth.
He respected him.
Your father did business with Hyman Roth,
he respected Hyman Roth,
but he never trusted Hyman Roth
or his Sicilian messenger boy Johnny Ola.
You'll have to excuse me. I'm tired, and I'm a little drunk!
I want everybody here to know,
there's not going to be no trouble from me!
Don Corleone.
Cicci, the door...
You want him to leave now?
Let him go back to New York.
I've already made my plans.
The old man had too much wine.
It's late.
How's the baby?
Sleeping inside me.
Does it feel like a boy?
Yes, it does, Michael.
Kay?
I'm sorry about all the people today.
Bad timing.It couldn't be helped, though.
It made me think of what you once told me.
"In five years the Corleone family will be completely legitimate."
That was seven years ago.
I know.
I'm trying, darling.
"Do you like it"
Did you see this?
Michael,why are the drapes open?
Kay, are you all right?
- Are you hit? - No.
It's over It's over.
Get the door locked!
Stop,stop...
They're still on the property.
Please stay inside.
Keep them alive.
- We'll try.-Alive!
Stay by the door.
Stay around house.
Yeah, come in.
Mike, are you all right?
- Yeah.
Yeah,there's a lot I can't tell you.
and I now that's upset you in the past.
A little.
You felt it was because of some lack of trust or confidence.
But it's...
because I admire you and love you,
that I kept things secret from you.
Now you're the only one I can trust.
Fredo?
Well, he's got a good heart.
But he's weak and he's stupid
nd this is life and death.
Tom, you're my brother.
I always wanted to be thought of as a brother by you, Mikey. A real brother.
I know that.
You're going to take over.
You're going to be the Don.
If what I think has happened,
I'm leaving here tonight.
I give you complete power.
Over Fredo and his men. Rocco, Neri, everyone.
I'm trusting you with the lives of my wife
and my children,
the future of this family.
If we catch them,
will we find out...
We won't catch them.
Unless I'm very wrong,
they're dead already.
They were killed by somebody close to us.
Inside.
Very,very frightened that they botched it.
You don't think that Rocco and Neri
had something to do with this?
See...
All our people are businessmen.
Their loyalty is based on that.
One thing I learned from Pop...
...was to try to think as people around you think.
On that basis, anything is possible.
Mike, they're dead! Right outside my window!
I want to get out of here.They're lying there dead!
Get her in!
Over here! There's two of them.
Looks like they were hired out of New York.
I don't recognise them.
Won't get anything out of them now.
Look,look...
Fish them out.
Get rid of the bodies.
Where's Mike?
Rocco.
Anthony, everything is going to be all right. Try to sleep.
Did you like your party?
- I got lots of presents.-I know.
Did you like them?
Yeah. I didn't know the people who gave them to me.
Well, they were friends.
Did you see my present for you?
It was on my pillow.
Anthony.
I'm going to be leaving very early tomorrow.
- Will you take me? - No, I can't, Anthony.
Why do you have to go?
I have to do business.
I could help you.
I know. Some day you will.
Get some sleep.
She's really beautiful.You've got to see her.
Wait till you see her. Words can't describe her.
I left Naples. I left Mama.
For a no-good tramp!
Now here I am in America, in New York.
Alone! Thinking of my mother.
Without news from home.
Enter!
Pepino, a letter for you!
Have a seat.
Finally, a letter from Naples!
Vito, how do you like my little angel?
Isn't she beautiful?
She's very beautiful.
To you, she's beautiful.
For me, there's only my wife and son.
And mama
Our dear mother is dead!
We'll go backstage later and take her to eat.
Sit down, you bum!
Oh, excuse me, Don Fanucci.
We'll go see her backstage.
-Who was that?-The Black Hand.
Vito,come on...
Come on let's go see her backstage.
Sorry,sorry...
Please.
That's Fanucci... the Black Hand.
We'll talk about it tomorrow.
Tomorrow! Always tomorrow!
You'll pay me today!
Let's go.
-Pay me now! -Not my daughter! Let her go!
Here, take all my money!
Vito, come on.
I know what you're thinking.
But you don't know how things are.
Fanucci's with the Black Hand.
The whole neighborhood pays him.
Even my father, in the grocery store.
If he's Italian...
...why does he bother other Italians?
He knows they have nobody to protect them.
Forget that. Did you like my angel?
If you're happy, I'm happy.
Don't you feel well?
Is your boss treating you all right?
Forget it.
Hey! Paisan!
Hey, you speak Italian?
Hide this for me!Next week. I'll come and get it!
Abbandando, meet my nephew!
How's business?
It's good, it's good.
Fanucci's mad. Says the neighborhood's getting sloppy.
People don't pay on time, don't pay the full amount.
Says he's been too nice to everyone.
So Fanucci's changing?
Sure. He wants double from everybody.
Even from my father.
I'm a friend, right?
So you'll let him work here?
Vito,come here.
I've got some bad news.
I feel rotten about telling you this...
But Fanucci... he's got a nephew...And you have to give him my job.
You've always been good to me, ever since I came here.
You looked after me like a father.
I thank you.And I won't forget it.
Vito!
No...
Oh, no!
Take this to your family.
Thanks anyway. But please, I can't accept.
-Take this to your family. -I can't accept.
No!
What a nice pear!
I'm Clemenza, you still have my goods?
Did you look inside?
I'm not interested in things that don't concern me.
A friend of mine has a nice rug.
Maybe your wife would like it.
Sure she would. But who has money for a rug?
It would be a present. I know how to return a favor.
Yeah,sure.My wife would like it.
Let's go
The son of a bitch! He isn't home!
Damn, he didn't even leave the key.
Well, he won't mind.
Come on in. Hey,Vito come on in.
Please come on in.
-This is your friend's place? -Yes.
This is a real palace.
One of the best.
Vito, give me a hand, will you?
Look how pretty it is, Santino!
Come on in.
It's all right. Hyman's in there.
Would you like a tuna sandwich?
No, thank you.
Mr. Roth?
Come in, Michael.
Sit down, make yourself comfortable.
It's almost over.
Do you follow the football game?
Not for a while I haven't.
I enjoy watching football in the afternoon.
One of the things I love about this country.
Baseball too.
Ever since Arnold Rothstein fixed the World Series in 1919.
I heard you had some trouble.
Stupid.
People behaving like that with guns.
The important thing is you're all right.
Good health is the most important thing.
More than success, more than money.
More than power.
I came here because there's going to be more bloodshed.
I wanted you to know
so another war won't start.
Nobody wants another war.
Frank Pentangeli asked my permission
to get rid of the Rosato brothers.
When I refused he tried to have me killed.
He was stupid, I was lucky.
I'll visit him soon.
The important thing is that nothing interferes with ourplans for the future.
Nothing is more important.
You're a wise and considerate man.
And you're a great man, Mr. Roth.
There's much I can learn from you.
Whatever I can do to help, Michael.
- Excuse me. Lunch. - Come in.
Thank you, my dear.
You're going to break your eardrums.
- Enjoy it. - Thank you.
You're young, I'm old and sick.
What we'll do in the next few months will make history.
It's never been done before.
Not even your father would dream that such a thing could be possible.
Frank Pentangeli is a dead man. You don't object?
He's small potatoes.
What's up?
We got company?
-Michael Corleone is here. -Michael Corleone?
He's in your den. You better hurry.
He's been waiting a half hour.
Is something wrong?
Don Corleone
I wish you would have let me know you were coming.
I could have prepared something.
I didn't want you to know.
You heard what happened?
I almost died.
-We were so relieved.-In my home!
In my bedroom where my wife sleeps!
Where my children come to play.
In my home.
I want you to help me take my revenge.
Michael, anything. What can I do?
Settle these troubles with the Rosato brothers.
I don't understand. I don't...
I don't have your brain
for big deals.
But this is a street thing.
That Hyman Roth in Miami. He's backing up those sons-of-bitches.
I know he is.
Then why?
So why ask me to lay down to them?
It was Hyman Roth that tried to have me killed.
I know it was him.
Jesus Christ, Mike.
Jesus Christ, let's get them all.
Now while we've got the muscle.
This used to be my father's old study.
It's changed.
I remember...
there used to be a big desk here.
I remember when I was a kid. We had to be quiet when we played near here.
I was very happy that this house never went to strangers.
First Clemenza took it over. Now you.
My father taught me many things here.
He taught me in this room.
He taught me, "Keep your friends close,
but your enemies closer."
If Hyman Roth sees that I interceded in this
in the Rosato brothers' favour
he'll think his relationship with me is still good.
-Capide? -Capide.
That's what I want him to think.
I want him relaxed
and confident in our friendship.
Then I'll be able to find out
who the traitor in my family was.
Fredo, this is Johnny Ola
We need some more help,Johnny
Johnny?
Jesus Christ, what the hell time is it?
Who's that, honey?
Listen good, Fredo,
Why are you calling me?
I don't want to talk to you.
Pentangeli is going to accept the Rosato brothers' deal
- Will he come alone?-I don't know.
You've got me in deep enough already.
Just go along,
everything will be all right,
Fredo,Pentangeli says he's willing to make a deal
All we want to know is if he's on the level, or if he'll bring his boys
You lied to me. I don't want you to call me anymore.
Your brother won't find out we talked
I don't know what you're talking about.
Who was that?
Wrong number.
Frankie, I've got nobody here.
Wait in the car, Cicc'.
- Frankie. - That's okay, Cicc'.
What's this?
A lucky C note for our new deal.
Ritchie. Give us a taste.
We were all real happy about your decision, Frankie.
You won't regret it.
I don't like the C note, Rosato.
I take that as an insult.
Michael Corleone says hello!
Close the door!
Your friend the cop...
Hey, Ritch. It's dark in here.
Are you open or closed?
I just came in to clean up a little, you know?
What's the matter?
Is that something on the floor?
Carmine, not here! Anthony!
You open this bar and I'll blow your head in!
Freddy, it's good to see you.
- How is he? - He's okay. He's in the back.
Girls, take a hike.
In this room here.
I want to talk to him alone first.
Come on.
I thought I could help you, Senator.
Hagen?
Listen, I did not...
It's all right.
I didn't do anything.
It's okay.
You're very lucky.
My brother Fredo operates this place.
He was called before anyone.
Had this happened some place else
we couldn't have helped you.
When I woke up, I was on the floor.
And I don't know how it happened.
You can't remember?
I passed out.
Just a game. Jesus.
Jesus, Jesus!
Jesus God!
Oh God!
I don't know, and I don't understand why
I can't remember.
Doesn't matter, just do as I say.
Put in a call to your office.
Explain that
you'll be there tomorrow.
You decided to spend the night at Michael Corleone's house in Tahoe.
I do remember that she was laughing.
We'd done it before
and I know that I could not have hurt that girl.
This girl has no family.
Nobody knows that she worked here.
It'll be as though she never existed.
All that's left is our friendship.
Yes?
Sorry, but we're not to let you through.
I'm just going to the market.
We'll pick up anything you want.
Whose orders are these?
Mr. Hagen's. He's coming.
I'll speak to him.
I wanted to explain, but I had business in Carson City.
It's Michael's request for your safety.
We'll get anything you need.
So I'm supposed to stay in my house?
No, within the compound will be fine.
We were going to New England.
That's off.
Am I a prisoner?
That's not how we see it, Kay.
Come on, kids. We're going back to the house.
Joe.
Cuba, Cuba!
Most respected gentlemen.
Welcome to Havana.
I want to thank this distinguished group of
American industrialists for continuing to work with Cuba
for the greatest period of prosperity
in her entire history.
Mr. William Shaw
representing the General Fruit Company.
Messrs Corngold and Dant
of United Telephone and Telegraph Company.
Mr. Petty
regional Vice President of the Pan American Mining Corporation.
Mr. Robert Allen of South American Sugar.
Mr. Michael Corleone of Nevada.
representing our associates in tourism and leisure activities.
And my old friend and associate from Florida.
Mr. Hyman Roth.
I would like to thank
United Telephone and Telegraph
for their Christmas gift.
A solid gold telephone.
Perhaps you gentlemen would like to look at it.
- Mr. President? - Yes?
Could you discuss the rebel activity
and what this can mean to our businesses?
- Of course. - Heavy stuff.
I assure you that
lthough the rebels have started
a campaign in Las Villas
my staff indicates, with assurance
that we'll drive them out of Santa Clara before the New Year.
I want to put you all at ease.
We will tolerate no guerrillas in the casinos or the swimming pools.
He said that they're making an arrest
and in a few minutes he'll let us through.
-Johnny.-It's nothing.
Just some lousy bandits.The police are cleaning them up.
Viva Fidel!
I hope my age is correct.
I'm always accurate about my age.
Make sure that everybody sees the cake before we cut it.
I'm very pleased
you're all able to come from such distances to be with me today.
When a man comes to this point in his life
he wants to turn over the things he's been blessed with.
Turn them over to friends
as a reward for the friends he's had.
and to make sure that
everything goes well after he's gone.
Not for years.
We'll see. The doctors would disagree
but what do they know?
These are wonderful things that we've achieved in Havana
and there's no limit to where we can go from here.
This kind of government knows how to help business,to encourage it.
The hotels here are bigger and swankier than
any of the joints in Vegas.
We can thank our friends in the Cuban government
which has put up half the cash with the Teamsters,on a dollar for dollar basis
and has relaxed restrictions on imports.
What I'm saying is
that we have now what we have always needed:
Real partnership with a government.
Smaller piece.
You all know Michael Corleone
and we all remember his father.
At the time of my retirement, or death
I turn over all my interests in the Havana operation
to his control.
But
all of you will share.
The Nacionale will go to the Lakeville Road Boys
the Capri to the Corleone family
the Sevilla Biltmore also
but Eddie Levine will bring in the Pennino brothers
Dino and Eddie, for a piece
and to handle the casino operations.
We've saved a piece for some friends in Nevada
to make sure that things go smoothly back home.
I want all of you to enjoy your cake.
So, enjoy!
Happy birthday!
I saw an interesting thing happen today.
A rebel was being arrested by the military police.
Rather than be taken alive, he exploded a grenade he had in his jacket.
He killed himself and took a captain of the command with him.
-Right,Johnny?-Those rebels are lunatics.
Maybe so.But it occurred to me,that the soldiers are paidto fight
the rebels aren't.
What does that tell you?
They can win.
This country has had rebels for 50 years.
It's in their blood.I know.
I've been coming here since the Twenties.
We were running molasses from Havana
when you were a baby.
The trucks were owned by your father.
Mikey.
I'd rather we talked about this when we're alone.
The two million never got to the island.
It mustn't be known that you held back the money
because you worried about the rebels.
Sit down, Michael. Sit down.
If I could only live to see it, to be there with you.
What I wouldn't give for 20 more years.
Here we are, protected.
Free to make our profits without Kefauver
the goddamn Justice Department and the FBI .
90 miles away
in partnership with a friendly government.
90 miles. It's nothing.
Just one small step for a man looking to
be President of the United States
and having the cash to make it possible.
Mikey!
we're bigger than U.S. Steel.
Mikey, how are you? Okay?
Hi! Freddie Corleone.
Mio frati
Jesus Christ, what a trip!
I thought, "What if somebody knows
what I've got in here".
Can you imagine that?
Two million dollars on the seat next to me.
- Excuse me. - It's okay.
You want to count it?
What's going on?
I'm totally in the dark.
The family is making an investment in Havana.
This is a gift for the President.
That's great! Havana's great.
It's my kind of town.
Anybody I know in Havana?
Don't know. Hyman Roth, Johnny Ola?
No. I've never met them.
Listen, Mikey, I'm kind of...
...kind of
nervous from the trip.
Can I get a drink or something?
I thought maybe we'd go out together.
I know a place where we can spend some time together.
Sometimes I think I should have married a woman like you did.
Like Kay.Have kids. Have a family.
For once in my life
be more like Pop..
It's not easy to be a son, Fredo.
It's not easy.
Mama used to say, "You don't belong to me."
"You were left on the doorstep by gypsies."Sometimes I think it's true.
You're no gypsy, Fredo.
Mikey... I...
I was mad at you.
Why didn't we spend time like this before?
You want a drink, right?
Waiter!
How do you say Banana Daquiri?
Banana Daquiri.
- That's it? - That's it.
Uno Banana Daquiri.
Banana Daquiri.
and a club soda.
Senator Geary flies in from Washington tomorrow
with some government people.
I want you to show them a good time in Havana.
That's my speciality, right?
Can I trust you with something?
Of course, Mike.
Later in the evening we're all invited to the President to bring in the New Year
After it's over they'll take me home in a military car
alone.For my protection.
Before I reach my hotel, I'll be assassinated.
- Who? - Roth.
It was Roth who tried to kill me in my home.
It was Roth all along.
He acts like I'm his son
his successor.
But he thinks he'll live forever
and wants me out.
How can I help?
Just go along, as if you know nothing.I've already made my move.
What move?
Hyman Roth won't see the New Year.
Says you have to take it easy.And he's gonna give you a prescription.
-He'll be back tomorrow. -I want my own doctor.
Fly in my own doctor from Miami.
I don't trust a doctor who can't speak English.
- Gracias, senor - Buenas noches
Honey, go to the casino.
If you're feeling better.
Feel fine.
Play the bingo game.
- Okay. Nice to see you, Mr. Paul.-
My sixth sense tells me Fredo
brought a bag full of money.
Where is it?
You're pulling out?
Just want to...
Just want to wait.
- How do you feel? - Terrible.
I'd give four million to be able
to take a painless piss.
Who had Frank Pentangeli killed?
The Rosato brothers.
I know, but who gave the go-ahead?
I know I didn't.
There was this kid I grew up with.
He was younger than me.
Sort of looked up to me
you know
We did our first work together.
Worked our way out of the street.
Things were good.
During Prohibition we ran molasses into Canada.Made a fortune.
Your father too.
As much as anyone, I loved him and
trusted him.
Later on he had an idea
to build a city
out of a desert stop-over for G.I.s going to the West Coast.
That kid's name was Moe Greene
and the city he invented was Las Vegas.
This was a great man.
A man of vision and guts.
And there isn't even a plaque, signpost
or statue of him in that town.
Someone put a bullet through his eye.
No one knows who gave the order.
When I heard it, I wasn't angry.
I knew Moe, I knew he was headstrong.
Talking loud, saying stupid things.
So when he turned up dead
I let it go.
And I said to myself
This is the business we've chosen.
I didn't ask
who gave the order
because it had nothing to do with business.
That two million in a bag in your room
I'm going in to take a nap.
When I wake
if the money is on the table
I know I have a partner.
If it isn't, I know I don't.
Does everybody know everybody?
This is senator Geary,you know him.
-How are you,senator? -Good to see you, Mike.
I'm glad we spend this time together.
Senator Payton from Florida
How ya doin', Mike?
Judge DeMalco from New York
-How do you do, Sir?-Fine, thank you.
Senator Ream from Maryland
Mike, I've been looking forward to it.
Fred Corngold from UTT.
I know Fred, how are you?
That Freddie does a mean Cha Cha Cha so watch out later.
Oh he does, huh?
Okay,gentlemen,it's refill time here.
You might try some of those local drinks,
you know "Cuba Libra"
"Pi?a Colada"
I think I'll try one of those red headed Yolandas.
That you got! Con gusto..
Johnny!
You don't know my brother Fredo.
Johnny Ola, Fredo.
We never met. Johnny Ola. Pleasure.
Gentlemen, to a night in Havana!
- Happy New Year! - Happy New Year!
- Feliz Ano Nuevo! - Happy New Year.
Hey, Freddie, why are we standing?
Everybody stands.
It's worth it. You won't believe this.
I don't believe it already.
50 dollars, right?
You've got a bet, mister.
That's Superman.
Did I tell you or did I tell you?
I don't believe it!
It's got to be fake.
It's real. That's why he's called Superman.
Hey, Freddy
where did you find this place?
Johnny Ola brought me here.
I didn't believe it
but seeing is believing!
I see it, but still don't believe it!
50 bucks, Pat.
Roth won't go here
but Johnny knows these places like the back of his hand.!
Now watch him,he's gonna break a cracked with it.
Break a cracker? I want to see him break a brick.
He could knock down a building.
Relax!Se?or Roth.
we're taking you to the hospital.
And in my judgment, you'll continue to get those,
because I don't believe
that President Eisenhower well ever pull out of Cuba
not as long as we have over one billion dollars
invested in this country.
The American public believe in non-intervention...
Fredo!
Where are you going?
I'm getting a real drink
because I can't...
What kept Mr. Roth?
I understood he was coming.
Reeves, what's the protocol?
How long should we stay?
I think a half hour ought to do it.
Just long enough to bring in the New Year.
It's New Year's Eve. Come on, just for a minute.
There's a plane waiting
to take us to Miami in an hour.
Don't make a big thing about it.
I know it was you, Fredo.
You broke my heart.
You broke my heart!
Due to serious setbacks to our troops in Guantanamo and Santiago
my position in Cuba is untenable.
I am resigning from office to avoid further bloodshed.
And I shall leave the city immediately.
I wish all of you good luck.
Fredo!Come on. Come with me.
It's the only way out of here tonight.
Roth is dead!Fredo.
Fredo, come with me!
You're still my brother.Fredo...
Passports,Passports,U.S. passports only, please.
Pass through, I'm Pat GEARY of the United States Senate!
-Get back! -Please, I must leave!
Al. Get me a wet towel.
Does Kay know I'm back?
My boy? Did you get him something for Christmas?
I took care of it.
What was it, so I'll know.
It was a little car with an electric motor that he can ride in.
It's nice.
Thank you, Al.
Fellows, could you step outside for a minute?
Where's my brother?
Roth got out on a private boat.
He's in a hospital in Miami.
He had a stroke, but recovered okay.
Your bodyguard is dead.
I asked about Fredo.
I think he got out. He must be somewhere in New York.
All right.
I want you to get in touch with him.
I know he's scared.
Tell him everything is all right.
Tell him I know Roth misled him.
That he didn't know they would try to kill me.
They can come in now.
There was something else.
What?
What? Come on.
Kay had a miscarriage.
Was it a boy?
At three and a half months.
Can't you give me a straight answer?!
Was it a boy?
I really don't know.
Poor little Fredo, he's got pneumonia.
Young man, I hear you and your friends are stealing goods.
But you don't even send a dress to my house.
No respect!
You know I've got three daughters.
This is my neighborhood.
You and your friends should show me some respect.
You should let me wet my beak a little.
I hear you and your friends
cleared $600 each.
Give me $200 each, for your own protection.
And I'll forget the insult.
You young punks have to learn
to respect a man like me!
Otherwise the cops will come to your house.
And your family will be ruined.
Of course if I'm wrong about how much you stole
I'll take a little less.And by less,I only mean a hundred bucks less.
Now don't refuse me.
-Understand, paesano? -I understand.
My friends and I share all the money.
So first, I have to talk to them.
Tell your friends
I don't want a lot. Just enough to wet my beak.
Don't be afraid to tell them!
600 bucks.
Suppose we don't pay?
You know his gang, Tessio.
Real animals.
Maranzalla himself let Fanucci work this neighborhood.
He's got connections with the cops, too.
We have to pay him.
$200 each...everybody agreed?
Why do we have to pay him?
Vito, leave this to us.
He's one person, we're three.
He's got guns, we've got guns.
Why should we give him the money we sweated for?
This is his neighborhood!
I know two bookies who don't give anything to Fanucci.
They don't pay Fanucci.
If they don't pay Fanucci
then somebody else collects for Maranzalla!
We'll all be better off if we pay him.
Don't worry.
Now what I say stays in this room.
If you both like
why not give me $50 each to pay Fanucci?
I guarantee he'll accept what I give him.
If Fanucci says $200
he means it, Vito!
I'll reason with him.
Leave everything to me.
I'll take care of everything.
I never lie to my friends.
Tomorrow you both go talk to Fanucci.
He'll ask for the money.
Tell him you'll pay whatever he wants.
Don't argue with him.
Then I'll go and get him to agree.
Don't argue with him, since he's so tough.
How can you get him to take less?
That's my business.
Just remember that I did you a favor.
-Is it a deal? -Si.
Salute.
His family's out of the house.
Fanucci's alone in the cafe.
Vito, here's my 50 dollars.
Buona fortuna,are you sure he's going to go for it?
I'll make an offer he don't refuse.
Don't worry.
It looks like there's - $100 under my hat.
I was right.Only $100...
I'm short of money right now.
I've been out of work,so just give me a little time.
You understand, don't you?
You've got balls, young man!
How come I never heard of you before?
You've got a lot of guts.
I'll find you some work for good money.
No hard feelings, right?
If I can help you, let me know.
Enjoy the festa!
Don FANUCCI.
Forzzelando!
Oh, this is too violent for me!
What've you got there?
Michael, your father loves you very much.
Mr. Cicci, from the year 1942 to the present time,
you were an employee of the Genco Olive Oil Company?
That's right.
But in actuality
you were a member of the Corleone crime organisation.
No, we called it the Corleone family,
Senator.we called it the family.
What was your position?
At first, like everybody else, I was a soldier.
What is that?
A button, you know, Senator.
No, I don't know. Tell me.
When the boss says "push a button" on a guy,
I push a button.
See, Senator?
Mr. Questadt.
-You mean you kill people? -?
You kill people at the behest of your superiors.
Yeah, that's right.
And the head of your family is Michael Corleone?
Yeah, Counsellor. Michael Corleone.
Did you ever get such an order
directly from Michael Corleone?
No, I never talked to him.
Mr. Cicci
Could you amplify your answer a bit?
Do what?
Could you expand on your answer?
I'm particularly interested in knowing, was there always a buffer involved?
Someone in between you and your superiors who gave the order.
Right, a buffer.
The family had a lot of buffers!
You may find this very amusing,
but the members of this committee do not.
Tell me something, Ma.What did Papa think deep in his heart?
He was being strong.
Strong for his family.
But by being strong for his family
could he lose it?
You're thinking about your wife about the baby you lost.
But you and your wife can always have another baby.
No, I meant... lose his family,
But you can never lose your family.
Times are changing.
It's my pleasure. I don't want money.
-Take it as a gift.-
If there's something I can do for you, you come, we talk.
Grazie.
Signora Colombo, why did you come to see me?
Your wife told me to ask if you could help me.
She's in bad trouble.
Her neighbors complained to the landlord about her dog.
He told her to get rid of the animal.
But her little boy loves that dog.
So she hid it.
When the landlord found out
he got mad and told her to leave.
Now she can't stay even if she gets rid of it.
I'm so ashamed!
He said he'd get the police to throw us out on the street.
I'm sorry, but...
I could give you a couple dollars to help you move.
I can't move!
I want you to talk to him!
Tell him I want to stay here!
What's your landlord's name?
His name is Signor Roberto.
He lives on Fourth Street, near here.
They break the windows, they dirty the floors...
A real pig-sty, eh?
Mr.Roberto
My name is Vito Corleone.
Signora Colombo is a friend of my wife.
She says she's been evicted for no good reason.
She's a poor widow, she has nobody to take care of her.
She has no relatives,no money.
All she has is this neighborhood.
I already rented the place to another family.
I told her that I'd talk to you.
That you're a reasonable man.
She got rid of the animal that caused all the trouble.
So let her stay.
-Are you Sicilian?-No, I'm Calabrese.
We're practically paesani, do me this favor.
I already rented it! I'll look like an idiot.
Besides, the new tenants pay more rent.
How much more a month?
Five bucks.
Here's six months increase in advance.
But don't tell her about it. She's very proud.
Come see me in another six months.
Of course, the dog stays. Right?
The dog stays.
Who the hell are you to come give me orders?
Watch out or I'll kick your Sicilian ass right into the street!
Do me this favor.I won't forget it.
Ask your friends in the neighborhood about me.
They'll tell you I know how to return a favor.
What a character!
That landlord is here... Roberto
the one who owns those ratholes.
He's been asking all around the neighborhood about you.
Grazie.
I hope I'm not disturbing you, Don Vito.
What can I do for you, Don Roberto?
What a misunderstanding! Holy Mary!
Of course Signora Colombo can stay!
Grazie...
I'm giving back the money you gave me.
Un, due, three, four, five, six, tutt'!
Because after all, Don Vito, money isn't everything.
Can I sit down?
Grazie.
Your kindness to that widow made me ashamed of myself.
The rent stays like before!
I'll even lower it.
I'll lower it $5.
I'll lower it $10!
Grazie...
Can I offer you some coffee?
I'm late for an appointment!
I can't this time! Ask me another time!
You'll have to excuse me for now.
I wish I could stay longer!
Just call me and I'll be here!
Grazie.
He won't be back. He'll hide out in the Bronx!
Vito, what do you think?
We'll make a big business!
-New York City.-We'll make a big business!
New York City.
- Are you the son of Vito Corleone? - Yes, I am.
Where was he born?
Corleone, Sicily.
Did he at times use an alias
that was known in certain circles as Godfather?
Godfather is a term used by his friends.
One of affection and respect.
Mr. Chairman
I would like to verify the witness' statement.
For years many of my constituents have been of Italian descent.
I've come to know them well.
They have honoured me with their support and their friendship.
I can proudly say
that some of my very best friends are Italian-Americans.
However, Mr. Chairman, unfortunately I have to leave these proceedings
in order to preside over a very important meeting
of my own committee.
Before I leave, I do want to say this
that these hearings on the Mafia are in no way whatsoever
a slur upon the great Italian people.
I can state from my own knowledge and experience
that Italian-Americans are among the most loyal,most law-abiding,
patriotic, hard-working American citizens in this land.
It would be a shame, Mr. Chairman
if we allowed a few rotten apples to give a bad nameto the whole barrel.
ecause from the time of Christopher Columbus
to the time of Enrico Fermi
Italian-Americans have been pioneers in building and defending our nation.
They are the salt of the earth
and one of the backbones of this country.
Here,
Here...
I think we all agree with our esteemed college.
Now,Mr. Corleone
you have been advised as to your legal rights.
We have testimony
from a previous witness
one Willi Cicci.
He stated hat you are head of
the most powerful Mafia family in the country.
- Are you? - No, I'm not.
He testified that you are personally responsible
for the murder of a New York police captain in 1947
and with him a man named Virgil Sollozzo.
- Do you deny this? - Yes, I do.
Is it true that in the year 1950 you devised the murder
of the heads of the "Five Families" in New York
who assume and consolidate your nefarious power?
It's a complete falsehood.
Mr. Questadt.
Is it true you have a controlling interest in three major hotels in Las Vegas?
No, it's not true.
I own some stock in some of the hotels there
but very little.
I also have stock in IBM and IT&T.
Mr. Corleone
Mr. Corleone do you have any interests or control over gambling or narcotics
-in the state of New York.? -No, I do not.
Senator, my client would like
to read a statement.
Mr. Chairman
Mr. Chairman,I think this statement is
totally out of order at this time.
Sir, my client has answered
this committee's questions with sincerity.
He hasn't taken
the Fifth Amendment
so this statement
should be heard!
No, I'll allow Mr. Corleone to read his statement.
I'll put it in the record.
In the hopes of clearing my family name
to give my children their
share of the American way of life
without a blemish on their name and background
I have appeared before this committee and given it all my cooperation.
I consider it a great personal dishonour to have to deny that I am a criminal.
I wish to have the following noted for the record:
That I served my country faithfully
in World War Two and was awarded
the Navy Cross for actions
in defence of my country.
That I have never been arrested or indicted for any crime.
That no proof linking me to any criminal conspiracy
whether it is called Mafia or Cosa Nostra
or any other name has ever been made public.
I have not taken refuge behind the Fifth Amendment
although I may do so.
I challenge this committee
to produce any witness or evidence against me
and if they do not
I hope they will have the decency
to clear my name with the same publicity
with which they have besmirched it.
I'm sure we're all quite impressed.
Particularly with your love for our country.
We'll be in recess until 10 a.m. Monday
when we will produce a witness
who'll corroborate the charges against you.
And at which time Mr.Corleone.
you may very well be subject to indictment for perjury.
I remind you that you're still under subpoena.Adjourned!
Ten-to-one shot, you said.
Ten-to-one shot
He would take the Fifth, and I lose.
You sound like my bookie.
I owe that monkey my life.
Well, just get a good night's sleep.
Yeah.
You've got a big day tomorrow.
I've got you a new suit, new shirt, new tie.
I'll shave you myself in the morning.
You'll look respectable for 50 million
of your fellow Americans.
Tomorrow... My life won't be worth a nickel after tomorrow.
Come on! I saw this 19 times.
You've got a great home here
for the rest of your life.Nobody gets near you
you're not going anywhere.
That's great. Beautiful.
Some deal I made.
You'll live like a king. You'll be a hero.
You'll live better here than most people outside.
Some deal!
Alive. Pentangeli is alive.
How did they get their hands on him?
Roth. He engineered it, Michael.
When Frankie went to make a deal with the Rosato brothers
they tried to kill him.
He thought you double-crossed him.
Our people with the detectives said he was half dead
scared,and shouted that you'd turned on him.
They already had him on possession
bookmaking, murder one and more.
The FBI has him airtight.
He's on an army base, 24 hour guards.
We can't get to him.
You've opened yourself to five counts of perjury.
What about Fredo? What does he know?
He says he doesn't know anything
and I believe him.
Roth, he... played this one beautifully.
I'm going to talk to Fredo.
I haven't got a lot to say, Mike.
We have time.
I was kept pretty much in the dark.
I didn't know all that much.
What about now?
Is there anything you can help me out with? Anything you can tell me now?
They've got Pentangeli.
I didn't know it was going to be a hit, Mike.
I swear to God I didn't know.
Johnny Ola bumped into me
in Beverly Hills.
He said that he wanted to talk.
He said that you and Roth were in on a big deal together.
And that there was something in it for me if I could help him out.
He said that you were being tough on the negotiations
but if they could get a little help
and close the deal fast
it would be good for the family.
And you believed that story?
You believed that?
He said there was something in it for me
-on my own! -I've always taken care of you, Fredo.
Taken care of me?!
You're my kid brother!You take care of me?
Did you ever think about that?
Did you ever once think about that?
Send Fredo off to do this
send Fredo off to do that!
Let Fredo take care of some Mickey Mouse nightclub somewhere.
Let Fredo fetch somebody at the airport!
I'm your older brother
but was stepped over!
- It's the way Pop wanted it.- It's not the way I wanted it!
I can handle things, I'm smart!
Not like everybody says.
Like dumb. I'm smart and I want respect!
Is there anything you can tell me about this investigation?
Anything more?
The senate lawyer, Questadt... He belongs to Roth.
Fredo...
...you're nothing to me now.
Not a brother, not a friend.
I don't want to know you, or what you do.
I don't want to see you at the hotels.
I don't want you near my house.
When you see our mother, I want to know in advance, so I won't be there.
You understand?
Mikey.
I don't want anything to happen to him while my mother's alive.
There's more people than at a ballgame in here.
Hey, there's Willi Cicci!
This committee will come to order!
State your name, please.
Frank Pentangeli.
Where were you born?
Pontenegro, it's outside of Palermo.
Where do you live now?
I live in an army barracks with the FBI guys.
We have here a witness
that will further testify,to Michael Corleone's
rule of a criminal empire
that controls all gambling.
This witness has had no buffer
between himself and Michael Corleone.
He can corroborate enough charges
for us to recommend
a charge of perjury
against Michael Corleone.
- Senator. - Thank you, Chairman.
Mr. Pentangeli...
Mr. Pentangeli.
Were you a member of the Corleone family?
Did you serve under Caporegime, Peter Clemenza,
and under Vito Corleone,also known as the Godfather?
I never knew any Godfather.
I have my own family.
Mr. Pentangeli, you...
You are contradicting
your own sworn statement.
I ask you again, sir
here and now under oath,
were you at any time a member of a crime organisation led by Michael Corleone?
I don't know nothing about that!
I was in the olive oil business with his father
but that was a long time ago.
We have a sworn affidavit.
Your sworn affidavit
that you murdered on the orders of Michael Corleone.
Do you deny this confession
and do you realise what will happen if you do?
The FBI guys promised me a deal
so I made up a lot of stuff about Michael Corleone
just to please them.
But it was all lies.
Everything!
They kept saying,"Michael Corleone did this"
and "Michael Corleone did that".
So I said, "Yeah, sure. Why not?"
Mr. Corleone
would you kindly identify
the gentleman sitting to your left?
I can answer that.
His name is Vincenzo Pentangeli.
Is he related to the witness?
He is, I believe, his brother.
Will he come forward and be sworn?
He doesn't understand English.
He came at his own expense
to aid his brother.
He's not under subpoena,and his reputation in his own country
is impeccable.
He knows nothing about this?
To my knowledge, nothing.
I'm going to find out what happened!
This committee is now adjourned.
The witness is excused.
Senator!
This committee owes an apology!
This committee owes an apology. Apology, Senator!
- Michael, excuse me. - Hello, darling.
The children are outside. We're going.
What do you mean? We're leaving tomorrow.
-Rocco?-I'll be in my room, Mike.
Michael, I'm not going back to Nevada.
I brought the children to say goodbye to you.
I'm very happy for you.
I always knew you were too smart
to let any of them beat you.
- Why don't you sit down? - No, I'm not going to stay long.
There are some things I'd like to talk to you about.
Things that have been on my mind
changes I want to make.
I think it's too late for changes, Michael.
I wasn't going to say anything...
-but now...- What do you mean, "too late"?
What really happened with Pentangeli?
His brother came and helped him.
I didn't even know he had a brother.
Where is he now?
He's on a plane, back to Sicily.
All he had to do was show his face.
It was between the brothers, Kay.
I had nothing to do with it.
Don't tell me you're going, Not you, not the kids
No,You're my wife and my children
I love you and won't allow it
You say you love me, but talk about allowing me to leave!
That have been going on for years between mean and women
that will not change an that's it.
-You've become blind! -Blind to what?
Look what's happened to us.
Mike!my God,
Look what's happened to our son, Michael.
-Nothing's happened to him. -Don't tell me nothing's...
-Anthony's fine. -Anthony's not fine!
-I don't wanna hear about it. -You will hear about it!
-I don't wanna hear about it! -Anthony's friends...
- I don't want to hear about it.- are your buttonmen!
I don't want to hear about it!
Over!
At this moment I feel no love for you at all.
I never thought that would ever happen
but it has.
Kay...
We're leaving tomorrow.
Why don't you take the kids back to their room?
Michael, you haven't heard me.
Kay, what do you want from me?
Do you expect me to let you go
to let you take my children from me?
Don't you know me?
Don't you know that
that's an impossibility?
That I'd use all my power to keep that from happening?
Don't you know that?
Kay..
In time
you'll feel differently.
You'll be glad I stopped you now.
I know that.
I know you blame me for losing the baby.
I know what that meant to you.
I'll make it up to you, Kay.
I swear I'll make it up to you. I'll...
I'm going to change.
I'll change.
I've learned that I have the strength to change.
Then you'll forget about this miscarriage...
...and we'll have another child.
And we'll go on, you and I.
We'll go on.
Oh, Michael!
Michael, you are blind.
It wasn't a miscarriage.It was an abortion.
An abortion, Michael. Just like our marriage is an abortion.
Something that's unholy and evil!
I didn't want your son, Michael!
I wouldn't bring another one of your sons into this world!
It was an abortion, Michael.
It was a son and I had it killed
because this must all end!
I know now that it's over.
I knew it then.
There would be no way, Michael
no way you could ever forgive me.
Not with this Sicilian thing that's been going on for 2,000...
- You won't take my children. - I will.
- You won't take my children! - They're my children too.
Hey,Sonny.what you doing,don't make a fight.
Ciccio
Don Ciccio
Don Ciccio, it's Tommasino.
Allow me the honor of introducing someone.
My partner in America, in New York.
His name is Vito Corleone.
We'll send him olive oil from here.
To his company in America.
They're olive oil importers, Don Ciccio.
We'd like your blessing
and your permission to start work.
Where is this young man from New York?
Have him come closer.
I can't see him so good.
My respects, Don Ciccio.
Give me your blessing.
Bless you!
What's your name?
Vito Corleone.
You took the name of this town!
And what's your father's name?
His name was... Antonio Andolini.
Louder, I don't hear so good.
My father's name was Antonio Andolini...
...and this is for you!
Michael, say goodbye.
Hi, Al.
Can I speak with you for a second, Tom?
Tom, where's Mike?
Waiting for you to leave.
Can I talk with him?
Sorry, Fredo. No chance.
- Can I see him? - He's in the boathouse.
Michael, it's Connie.
Michael
I'd like to stay close to home now, if it's all right.
Is Kay coming?
No.
Fredo's in the house with Mama.
He asked for you and Tom said you wouldn't see him.
That's right.
Kids, why don't you go outside for a while?
Please, I want to talk to you.
Michael, I hated you for so many years.
I think I did things to myself, to hurt myself
so that you'd know that I could hurt you.
You were just being strong for all of us,the way Papa was.
And I forgive you.
Can't you forgive Fredo?
He's so sweet
and helpless without you.
You need me.
I want to take care of you now.
Connie...
Tom, sit down.
Our friend and business partner,Hyman Roth, is in the news.
Did you hear about it?
I hear that he's in Israel.
The High Court in Israel
turned down his request to live there.
His passport's been invalidated,except to return here.
He landed in Buenos Aires yesterday.
He offered them a million dollars if they'd let him live there.
They turned him down.
He's going to try Panama.
Panama won't take him.
Not for a million, not for ten million
His condition is reported as terminal.
He's only got six months left.
He's had the same heart attack for 20 years.
That plane goes to Miami.
That's right. That's where I want it met.
Impossible.
They'll turn him over to the Internal Revenue
Customs and FBI.
It's not impossible.
Nothing's impossible.
There's no way we can get to him!
Tom, you surprise me.
If anything in this life is certain...
...if history has taught us anything...
...it's that you can kill anyone.
Rocco?
Difficult. Not impossible.
Good.
Why did you ask me if something was wrong when I came in?
I thought you were going to tell me
that you're moving your family to Vegas
and that you'd been offered the Vice Presidency of the Houstan hotels there.
- I thought you'd tell me that. -I turned them down.
Must I tell you every offer I turn down?
- Let's do business. - All right.
Just consider this, Michael.Just consider it.
Roth and the Rosatos are on the run.
Are they worth it, are we strong enough?
Is it worth it?
You've won. Do you want to wipe everybody out?
I don't feel I have to wipe everybody out, Tom.
Just my enemies, that's all.
Are you with me in these things, or what?
Because if not
you can take your wife, your family
and your mistress
and move them all to Las Vegas.
Why do you hurt me, Michael?
I've always been loyal to you.
What is this?
So... you're staying?
-Yes, I'm staying.-Okay.
What do you want me to do?
Anthony
Hey, Anthony...
How would you like it if I taught you how to catch the really big fish?
- Would you like that? - Okay.
You know, when I was your age...
...I went out fishing with all my brothers
and my father. Everybody.
I was the only one that caught a fish.
Nobody else could catch one.
Do you know how I did it?
Every time I put the line in the water
I said a Hail Mary
and every time I said a Hail Mary, I caught a fish.
Do you believe that?
It's true. That's the secret.
Do you want to try it out on the lake?
- Okay.- Okay.
What else have you got?
Everything will be okay.
Did my brother go back?
Yeah, don't worry.
He's ten times tougher than me, my brother.
He's old-fashioned.
He didn't want dinner
just wanted to go home.
That's my brother!
Nothing could get him away from that two-mule town.
He could have been big here. He could have had his own family.
Tom,what do I do now?
Frankie
You were always interested in politics and history.
I remember you talking about Hitler back in '33.
Yeah, I still read a lot. I get good stuff in there.
You were around the old-timers
who built the organisation of the families
basing them on the old Roman legions
with "regimes", "capos" and "soldiers".
And it worked.
Yeah, it worked.
Those were the great old days, you know.
We was like the Roman Empire.
The Corleone family was like the Roman Empire.
Yeah,it was once.
Frankie
When a plot against the Emperor failed...
...the plotters were always given a chance...
...to let their families keep their fortunes. Right?
Only the rich guys.
The little guys got knocked off
and all their estates went to the Emperors.
Unless they went home and killed themselves
then nothing happened.
And their families
were taken care of.Tom.
That was a good break, a nice deal.
They went home...
and sat in a hot bath
opened up their veins and bled to death.
And sometimes they had a little party before they did it.
Don't worry about anything, Frankie Five-Angels.
Thanks, Tom. Thanks.
See you, Tom.
Addio, Frankie.
Kay... You have to go.
So pretty
Kay, please hurry. He's coming.
Anthony... Kiss Mama goodbye.
Anthony,would you kiss your mother good bye.
Anthony,say good bye to mama,Anthony
honey I love you.
Kay, please.
All right.
Mary, come here.
Anthony, please. Kiss me once.
Easy.
Anthony! Anthony!
He's here we're going fishing!
No.Michael want to take him to Reno now.
Shit!
Okay, kid, you have to go to Reno with your pop.
I'll take you fishing tomorrow
-Okay? - Okay.
That a boy.
Hey, Anthony,Listen, I'll catch one for you in secret.
-Okay? - Okay.
Let's go.
Al let's go .
Mr. Roth, I must take you into custody.
I understand.
What's your reaction to
the Israeli High Court ruling?
I'm a retired investor on a pension.
I went to Israel to live there as a Jew
in the twilight of my life.
Hey, Frankie! Come on out, let's play some Hearts.
Frankie!
Is it true you're worth over 300 million dollars?
I'm a retired investor, living on a pension.
I came home to vote in the presidential election
because they wouldn't give me an absentee ballot.
Halt!
Jesus Christ.
Hail Mary, full of grace.
The Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women.
Blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of God, pray for us sinners.
Hey! Everybody, pay attention.
This is my friend Carlo Rizzi.
You know my brother Fredo.
- Sure.-This is my stepbrother Tom
and that's his girl Theresa.
This cute little thing is my sister Connie.
Say hello to Carlo.
-He's good-looking? - Yes.
The droopy thing is Mike.
We call him Joe College.
-Sit down. Talk to each other.
Hey, Mr. Einstein...
- The cake. - Sally, get in here!
- I was scared. - Come on.
Where's your father?
- Christmas shopping. -
Let's see that thing.
That's nice!
- Should I put the candles on now? -Yea go on.
- Yeah. You help her, Carlo. - Sure.
Hello,Tessio.
What is that? Rum?
Yeah.
Hey Sonny,don't touch the ante-pasta until Pop gets here.
Yea, come on.
What do you think of the nerve of those Japs?
those slanty eyed bastards, huh.
Dropping bombs in out back yard and on Pops birthday ya know.
Now they didn't know it was Pop's birthday. They didn't know it was Pop's birthday.
Not surprising after the oil embargo.
What do you mean expect it,
expect it or not they have no right dropping bombs.
What are you a Jap lover or something are you on their side?
I understand 30,000 enlisted this morning.
Bunch of saps
Why are they saps?
Sonny,come on.We don't have to talk about the war.
Hey beat it,you go talk to Carlo alright.
They're saps
because they risk their lives for strangers.
Now that's Pop talking..
You're god damn right that's Pop talking.
They risk their lives for their country.
Country isn't your blood, you remember that.
I don't feel that way.
Well if you don't fell that way
why don't you just quit collage and go to...go to join the Army.
I did.I've enlisted in the Marines.
Why didn't you come to us?
What do you mean?
I mean Pop had to pull a lot of strings
-to get you a deferment. - I didn't ask for it.
and I didn't want it.
-What's wrong?-Come on! Knock it off!
-Sonny -Punk!
- Sonny, sit down. - Sit down.
Mommy, Daddy's fighting again!
Go and show Carlo the tree.
Uncle Miclael,mama,pop.
Nice,real nice,break your fathers heart on his birthday.
That's swell, Mike. Congratulations.
Go on encourage him.
I want...I want you to get me a drink,go on.
Now you don't understand but, uh, your father has big plans for you.
Now many times he and I have talked about your future.
-Talked to my father about my future? -Yes.
My future?
Mikey, he has high hopes for you.
Well I have my own plans for my future.
What'd you go to collage to get stupid? You're really stupid.
He's here come on.
Come on...
Stupid!
Surprise!